<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>New Blog on Blowfish</title><link>https://localhost:1313/projects/</link><description>Recent content in New Blog on Blowfish</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</managingEditor><webMaster>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aranyak Parva Explorations - Mahabharata Book 3</title><link>https://localhost:1313/mahabharat/mahabharata-aranyak-parva-exploration-with-qa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/mahabharat/mahabharata-aranyak-parva-exploration-with-qa/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://localhost:1313/assets/images/projects/Mahabharata-Book3-bookCover.jpg" alt="Book: Aranyak Parva Explorations : Mahabharata Book 1">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="series-mahabharata-unveiled--qa-edition">Series: Mahabharata Unveiled : Q&amp;amp;A Edition&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#series-mahabharata-unveiled--qa-edition" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="book-title-aranyaka-parva-explorations---mahabharat-book-3">Book Title: Aranyaka Parva Explorations - Mahabharat Book 3&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#book-title-aranyaka-parva-explorations---mahabharat-book-3" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="dive-into-lengthy-topics-with-short-questions-and-answers">Dive into Lengthy Topics with Short Questions and Answers&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#dive-into-lengthy-topics-with-short-questions-and-answers" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.in/dp/B0CRZB5D5W">Kindle Read India&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRZB5D5W">Kindle Read US&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0CRZB5D5W">Kindle Read UK&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Book: Adi Parva Explorations : Mahabharata Book 1</title><link>https://localhost:1313/mahabharat/mahabharata-adi-parva-exploration-with-qa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/mahabharat/mahabharata-adi-parva-exploration-with-qa/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://localhost:1313/assets/images/projects/Mahabharata-Book1-bookCover3.jpg" alt="Book: Adi Parva Explorations : Mahabharata Book 1">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="series-mahabharata-unveiled--qa-edition">Series: Mahabharata Unveiled : Q&amp;amp;A Edition&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#series-mahabharata-unveiled--qa-edition" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="book-title-adi-parva-explorations---book-1">Book Title: Adi Parva Explorations - Book 1&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#book-title-adi-parva-explorations---book-1" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="dive-into-lengthy-topics-with-short-questions-and-answers">Dive into Lengthy Topics with Short Questions and Answers&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#dive-into-lengthy-topics-with-short-questions-and-answers" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.in/dp/B0CRS8K34P">Kindle Read India&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRS8K34P">Kindle Read US&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0CRS8K34P">Kindle Read UK&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Book: Wisdom in Awareness - Quotations for the Clarity</title><link>https://localhost:1313/Wisdom-in-Awareness-Quotations-for-the-Clarity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/Wisdom-in-Awareness-Quotations-for-the-Clarity/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://localhost:1313/assets/images/projects/WIAQfC-Coverpage2.jpg" alt="Book: Windom in Awareness - Quotations for the Clarity">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="book-wisdom-in-awareness">Book: Wisdom in Awareness&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#book-wisdom-in-awareness" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="quotations-and-passages-for-the-clarity">Quotations and Passages for the Clarity&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#quotations-and-passages-for-the-clarity" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.in/dp/B0CRHX2D12">Kindle Read India&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRHX2D12">Kindle Read US&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0CRHX2D12">Kindle Read UK&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sabha Parva Explorations - Mahabharata Book 3</title><link>https://localhost:1313/mahabharat/mahabharata-sabha-parva-exploration-with-qa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/mahabharat/mahabharata-sabha-parva-exploration-with-qa/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://localhost:1313/assets/images/projects/Mahabharata-Book2-bookCover.jpg" alt="Book: Sabha Parva Explorations : Mahabharata Book 1">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="series-mahabharata-unveiled--qa-edition">Series: Mahabharata Unveiled : Q&amp;amp;A Edition&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#series-mahabharata-unveiled--qa-edition" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="book-title-sabha-parva-explorations---mahabharat-book-2">Book Title: Sabha Parva Explorations - Mahabharat Book 2&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#book-title-sabha-parva-explorations---mahabharat-book-2" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="dive-into-lengthy-topics-with-short-questions-and-answers">Dive into Lengthy Topics with Short Questions and Answers&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#dive-into-lengthy-topics-with-short-questions-and-answers" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.in/dp/B0CSCSJ2ZG">Kindle Read India&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSCSJ2ZG">Kindle Read US&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0CSCSJ2ZG">Kindle Read UK&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Book: Mindful Project Management</title><link>https://localhost:1313/mindful-project-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/mindful-project-management/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://localhost:1313/assets/images/projects/mfpm-Coverpage1.jpg" alt="Book: Mindful Projet Management">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="book-mindful-projet-management">Book: Mindful Projet Management&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#book-mindful-projet-management" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="voyage-of-a-project-manager">Voyage of a Project Manager&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#voyage-of-a-project-manager" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.in/dp/B0CQ37294Y">Kindle Read India&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CQ37294Y">Kindle Read US&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0CQ37294Y">Kindle Read UK&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our modern era, a tragic trend has emerged where humans are growing increasingly desensitized and losing their inclination for deeper thought. We reside in an age of abundant information and rapidity, yet we struggle to derive meaning from this wealth of data, failing to assess the value in our pursuits and objectives. We live mechanically, skimming through endless information, social media platforms, and journeys without purposeful contemplation. We traverse through life&amp;rsquo;s milestones—education, career, marriage, wealth acquisition—unmindfully, forgetting our potential for a more purposeful existence. As the most intelligent beings known to the cosmos, we have the power to imbue life&amp;rsquo;s events with significance. After engaging with this book, your surroundings may remain unchanged, but a shift in your thought patterns can revolutionize your world, and this transformation can extend its value to others.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Research: AI Powered Historical Book Question Answering</title><link>https://localhost:1313/AI-Powered-Historical-Book-Question-Answering/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/AI-Powered-Historical-Book-Question-Answering/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://localhost:1313/assets/images/projects/AI-Powered-Historical-Book-Question-Answering.jpg" alt="AI-Powered-Historical-Book-Question-Answering">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="research-ai-powered-historical-book-question-answering">Research: AI Powered Historical Book Question Answering&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#research-ai-powered-historical-book-question-answering" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#abstract" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the recent past, we have seen a number of approaches, datasets, models, and even large language models (LLM) used for question-answering. The results of these initiatives are very encouraging, but generating questions from the given document, and generating a correct answer to a given question from a given document, is still challenging. It becomes more challenging when the text is historical, and it is translated from another language and a different script is used to write the translation than the script of the original text. This problem is because of the spelling of nouns in the original script. Secondly generating description answers and evaluating the correctness of descriptive answers is a challenge. Thirdly, if n number of question-answer pairs are generated from a certain corpus then how do you measure the performance of this model? Finally, if we have a large body of text and some questions in our mind then without giving the context how to get the answer? In this work, we are exploring techniques for creating questions and answers for a book corpus using ChatGPT and other available techniques, we call this QAGS. Secondly, we are finetuning the t5, flan-t5 model for creating an answer generation system, we call this AGS. Thirdly we are retrieving a relevant document that can answer a question in our hand, we call this DRS. Finally, we are creating and evaluating a system that can answer a history question without any context, we call this RAAGS. In this work, we are using The Mahabharata book as a corpus. To evaluate the different sub-systems we have used different metrics like BLEU, ROUGE, Accuracy, Recall, R@n, P@n, F1@n, Cosine. We have used SentenceTransformer for text embedding. Our approach does not depend upon the domain, script, or language of the text document. Neither, does it depend upon the Era when the text was written. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t need any manual feature engineering of the text. We have explored SOTA transformers like T5, distilBERT, RoBERTa, Bloom, BERT, BigBird from huggingface for zeroshot learning. The cosine between answer &amp;amp; question, answer &amp;amp; chunk is 0.91. In DRS MRR metric is 0.55, and MAP is 0.25. In AGS cosine between the reference answer and predicted answer is 0.827. In RAAGS cosine between the reference answer and the predicted answer is 0.763&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Research: Sarcasm Detection System for Hinglish Language</title><link>https://localhost:1313/Sarcasm-Detection-System-for-Hinglish-Language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/Sarcasm-Detection-System-for-Hinglish-Language/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://localhost:1313/assets/images/projects/Sarcasm-Detection-System-for-Hinglish-Language.jpg" alt="Sarcasm-Detection-System-for-Hinglish-Language">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="research-sarcasm-detection-system-for-hinglish-language">Research: Sarcasm Detection System for Hinglish Language&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#research-sarcasm-detection-system-for-hinglish-language" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#abstract" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Hinglish is third most spoken language on the planet. Wikipage, states that 65% of Indian population is under 35 years age. Several disruptions like low cost mobile phone, extremely cheap data, digital India initiatives by government of India has caused huge surge in Hinglish language content. Hinglish language context is available in audio, video, images, and text format. We can find Hinglish content in comment box of product, new articles, service feedback, WhatsApp, social media like YouTube, Facebook, twitter etc. To engage with consumer, it is extremely important to analyse the sentiments, but to perform sentiment analysis it is not possible to read every comment or feedback using human eyes. With the increasing number of education and sophisticated people in Indian society it is evident that people do not say negative things directly even when they want to say. Generally, an educated and advance mind is more diplomatic than less educated or village people who are not exposed enough to the world. Due to this reason people use more sarcastic language, they say negative things in positive words. Thus, it becomes necessary to identify the true sentiments in the text available on social media or product review or comment pages. In this paper we are demonstrating a system which can help in automatic sarcasm detection in Hinglish language. This work is also extracting text from Hindi twitter handles and Hindi blogs and creating a dataset. The dataset contains the tweets which are written in Roman or Devanagari scripts, words can be from any Indian language or English. In this research no word, either Indian language words written in Roman or English word written in Devanagari is translated or transliterated. A series of data cleaning activities are performed on the text extracted from blogs and twitter. We developed our dataset with the help of 3 Hinglish language speakers. Ten embeddings were built in this work. Four embeddings were finetuned using Transfer embedding, another four embedding were built using training data and standard NLP libraries, one from lexical features and one from lexical features + best embedding. In this work we used ten classification libraries for classification work. In total we developed 109 classification models and analysed the performance of those models against the embedding and classifier used. Four classification models were developed using neural network. Our best model with fastTextWiki embedding and Naïve Bayesian classifier gives 76% accuracy, 78% recall, 75% precision, 76% F1 score and 80% AUC.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>