<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ML Models on Blowfish</title><link>https://dasarpai.github.io/tags/ml-models/</link><description>Recent content in ML Models on Blowfish</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</managingEditor><webMaster>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dasarpai.github.io/tags/ml-models/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ML Model Respository from Pinto0309</title><link>https://dasarpai.github.io/dsblog/ML-Model-Repository-from-Pinto0309/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://dasarpai.github.io/dsblog/ML-Model-Repository-from-Pinto0309/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../assets/images/dspost/dsp6095-ML-Model-Repository-from-Pinto0309.jpg" alt="ML Model Respository from Pinto0309">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="ml-model-repository-from-pinto0309">ML Model Repository from Pinto0309&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#ml-model-repository-from-pinto0309" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#introduction" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Using AI we can solve many kinds of tasks for this input can be text, structured data, image, video, audio, time-series, etc. To solve these problems we need to train model. These models may be computer vision, NLP, or traditional machine learning kind. There are hundreds of architectures and algorithms to solve business problems and create models. There a hundreds of different datasets that can be along with a particular architecture or algorithm to solve the problem. If you have any of these tasks then you can explore using these pre-trained models to solve your problem. There is a GitHub user &amp;ldquo;Katsuya Hyodo&amp;rdquo; with GitHub account &amp;ldquo;PINTO0309&amp;rdquo;. He has trained hundreds of models and created these pre-trained models for the community. You can scan and explore them from there. From there you can download the pre-trained models.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Model Garden of VertexAI</title><link>https://dasarpai.github.io/dsblog/Model-Garden-of-VertexAI/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://dasarpai.github.io/dsblog/Model-Garden-of-VertexAI/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../assets/images/dspost/dsp6065-Model-Garden-of-VertexAI.jpg" alt="All Resources to Learn Data Science">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="model-garden-of-vertexai">Model Garden of VertexAI:&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#model-garden-of-vertexai" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="unlocking-the-power-of-googles-vertexai-exploring-the-world-of-pre-built-models-for-ai-tasks">Unlocking the Power of Google&amp;rsquo;s VertexAI: Exploring the World of Pre-Built Models for AI Tasks&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#unlocking-the-power-of-googles-vertexai-exploring-the-world-of-pre-built-models-for-ai-tasks" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction:&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#introduction" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Artificial Intelligence (AI) has transformed numerous industries, from healthcare and finance to e-commerce, logistic, eduction and entertainment. But the complexity of developing machine learning models often poses a challenge. As the demand for AI-powered solutions continues to rise, data scientists seek efficient ways to leverage pre-trained models or build custom models to address specific tasks. In this regard, Google&amp;rsquo;s VertexAI emerges as a robust platform that offers an extensive selection of pre-built models for a wide range of AI tasks. VertexAI platform has revolutionized the landscape by seamlessly leveraging LLM (Large Language Models) and Prompt Engineering techniques to perform complex machine learning tasks effortlessly. With VertexAI, data scientists can harness the power of state-of-the-art language models, such as LLM, to accelerate their ML development process. Additionally, the innovative concept of Prompt Engineering enables users to effectively communicate with the models, guiding them to deliver precise and accurate results. From computer vision and natural language processing to speech processing and structured tabular data analysis, Vertex AI&amp;rsquo;s repertoire includes over 100 models catering to diverse application domains. This article explores how Vertex AI, through its integration of LLM and Prompt Engineering, empowers users to effortlessly tackle intricate machine learning tasks across diverse domains, revolutionizing the AI development experience.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>