<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Project Management Best Practices on Blowfish</title><link>https://localhost:1313/tags/project-management-best-practices/</link><description>Recent content in Project Management Best Practices on Blowfish</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</managingEditor><webMaster>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 14:35:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://localhost:1313/tags/project-management-best-practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Best Practices of Project Management</title><link>https://localhost:1313/pmblog/Best-Practices-of-Project-Management/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 14:35:03 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/pmblog/Best-Practices-of-Project-Management/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://localhost:1313/assets/images/pmblog/1022-IT-PM-Best-Practices-min.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="40-commandments-of-project-management">40 Commandments of Project Management&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#40-commandments-of-project-management" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In this article, I am trying to put &lt;strong>Best Practices of Project Management&lt;/strong> in the form of &lt;strong>40 Commandments of Project Management&lt;/strong>. Project management is a complete subject like marketing, finance, or operation. It is not possible to bind do and don’t of this profession in certain commandments. But to begin with or in the absence of any formal project management system in place if a project manager pays attention to following practices s/he will be able to manage with the least pain to him, his team, and customer. My delivery experience on the business side has been in IT projects but being a project management trainer I meet people across the industry and they share their own good or bad stories. Based on all the inputs I received and my experience I and trying to put these practices in the shortest possible way. I understand there are many things that are not mentioned or elaborated enough therefore if you need any clarification or help you can write in the comment box or connect with me.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>