<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PhD Journey on Blowfish</title><link>https://localhost:1313/tags/phd-journey/</link><description>Recent content in PhD Journey on Blowfish</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</managingEditor><webMaster>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://localhost:1313/tags/phd-journey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Journey from Master to PhD in Data Science and AI</title><link>https://localhost:1313/dsblog/journey-from-master-to-phd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/dsblog/journey-from-master-to-phd/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://localhost:1313/assets/images/dspost/dsp6100-Journey-from-MS-to-Phd.jpg" alt="My Journey from Master to PhD in Data Science and AI">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="my-journey-from-master-to-phd-in-data-science-and-ai">My Journey from Master to PhD in Data Science and AI&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#my-journey-from-master-to-phd-in-data-science-and-ai" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I have been in software development between 1993 to 2009. Some of these years were in senior leadership roles in delivery management, project management, CMMI, ISO, ISMS, PMO, etc. In 2010 I moved into project management training and consulting. In 2018, I was considering going back to technology but this time I wanted to pick up a completely new stack of technology. I decided I would move into Data Science and AI. I knew AI as much as any typical software development person in senior management knew about this. It means I was highly confident that I could pick this up quickly. On top of that lots of content is available on the internet, many YouTube channels, and many courses are available. I thought it should be a cakewalk for me. I started learning this technology in my own way in my committed free time. Within 5-6 months after lots of study I started realizing this was the way to get the knowledge but it could not help me get confident to solve the problem. The more I learned, the more I felt that I did not know how much I needed to learn or how far I needed to go.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>