<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Privacy on Blowfish</title><link>https://dasarpai.github.io/tags/data-privacy/</link><description>Recent content in Data Privacy on Blowfish</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</managingEditor><webMaster>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dasarpai.github.io/tags/data-privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exploring Synthetic Data Generation Capabilities</title><link>https://dasarpai.github.io/dsblog/Exploring-Synthetic-Data-Generation-Capabilities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://dasarpai.github.io/dsblog/Exploring-Synthetic-Data-Generation-Capabilities/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../assets/images/dspost/dsp6163-Exploring-Synthetic-Data-Generation-Capabilities.jpg" alt="Exploring Synthetic Data Generation Capabilities">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="exploring-synthetic-data-generation-capabilities">Exploring Synthetic Data Generation Capabilities&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#exploring-synthetic-data-generation-capabilities" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="is-this-article-for-me">Is this article for me?&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#is-this-article-for-me" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Are you looking answers to these questions?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>What is Synthetic Data?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What is data anonymization?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What are different techniques for generating Anonymized Data?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Why is anonymizing not sufficient to address PII data issues?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When there is lots of data available around then why do we need synthetic data?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What are the challenges in synthetic data generation?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What are the tools for Synthetic Data Generator for Marketing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What are the tools for Graph Synthetic Data generation?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>List of popular synthetic data generation tools for different industries&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-synthetic-data">What is Synthetic Data?&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#what-is-synthetic-data" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Synthetic data&lt;/strong> is artificially generated data that mimics the characteristics and statistical properties of real-world data but is not derived directly from real-world events or observations. It is created using algorithms, simulations, or models to represent patterns, structures, and relationships found in actual datasets. Synthetic data can take various forms, such as text, images, audio, or structured tabular data, depending on the context. It is used across various industries to train AI models, simulate environments, and conduct research.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dealing with Sensitive Data</title><link>https://dasarpai.github.io/dsblog/2020-03-10-6001-dealing-with-sensitive-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 15:50:00 +0530</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://dasarpai.github.io/dsblog/2020-03-10-6001-dealing-with-sensitive-data/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../assets/images/dspost/dsp6001-Dealing-with-Sensitive-Data.jpg" alt="XAI">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="dealing-with-sensitive-data">Dealing with Sensitive Data&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#dealing-with-sensitive-data" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#introduction" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the biggest problems for a Data Science project team is to protect the data. We know, data is the basic raw material for building any supervised or unsupervised models. We cannot make a without data. Let’s assume you are working for an eCommerce retail company like Amazon; or in the health domain with some big hospital chain or government hospital; or in the banking industry with some big bank like Bank of America, Standard Charted, SBI, or ICICI Bank. They have huge data. That data can be used to develop ML models. These models can help them to serve their customers or other stakeholders in a better and efficient way. To develop these models, data should be given to the Data Science team. When the data is moving out from the production environment to the project environment, there is no guarantee that data will not fall in the wrong hands and will not be misused during the project or post the project completion. When the data is moving within the same company, there are lesser chances of this disaster. But when the company is giving data to third parties or vendors, then there are high chances.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>