<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Interview on Blowfish</title><link>https://localhost:1313/tags/interview/</link><description>Recent content in Interview on Blowfish</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</managingEditor><webMaster>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://localhost:1313/tags/interview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dr. Jaishankar's Interview with HT after US Election</title><link>https://localhost:1313/booksummary/Dr-Jaishankdar-Interview-with-HT-after-US-Election-06-03-2025/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/booksummary/Dr-Jaishankdar-Interview-with-HT-after-US-Election-06-03-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://localhost:1313/assets/images/booksummary/7546-Dr-Jaishankdar-Interview-with-HT-after-US-Election.jpg" alt="Dr. S. Jaishankar’s Interview with Bronwen Maddox about Geopolitics and India’s Global Rise after US Election">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=baGAw58Lb58">Full Event: Jaishankar&amp;rsquo;s Big Message To Trump, Says This On Ukraine War&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="summary-of-talk">Summary of Talk&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#summary-of-talk" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Introduction and Geopolitical Context&lt;/em>: Bronwen Maddox welcomes Dr. S. Jaishankar, India’s External Affairs Minister, at Chatham House to discuss India’s global rise. The conversation begins with geopolitics, focusing on the first 41 days of the Trump administration’s foreign policy, which Jaishankar finds unsurprising and promising for India due to its move toward multipolarity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Balancing Act - AI Regulation</title><link>https://localhost:1313/booksummary/The-Balancing-Act-AI-Regulation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/booksummary/The-Balancing-Act-AI-Regulation/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://localhost:1313/assets/images/booksummary/7544-The-Balancing-Act-AI-Regulation.jpg" alt="The Balancing Act - AI Regulation">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="the-balancing-act---ai-regulation">The Balancing Act - AI Regulation&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#the-balancing-act---ai-regulation" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="questions-of-this-interview">Questions of this Interview&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#questions-of-this-interview" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Below is a list of direct questions posed by the interviewer (Professor Hannah Fry) to Nicklas Lundblad (Deepmind)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interview: Yuval Noah Harari with BeerBiceps</title><link>https://localhost:1313/booksummary/Interview-Yuval-Noah-Harari-with-BeerBiceps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/booksummary/Interview-Yuval-Noah-Harari-with-BeerBiceps/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://localhost:1313/assets/images/booksummary/7543-Interview-Yuval-Noah-Harari-with-BeerBiceps.jpg" alt="Interview: Yuval Noah Harari with BeerBiceps">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="interview-yuval-noah-harari-with-beerbiceps--my-critiques">Interview: Yuval Noah Harari with BeerBiceps &amp;amp; My Critiques&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#interview-yuval-noah-harari-with-beerbiceps--my-critiques" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="questions-asked-to-yuval-noah-harari">Questions Asked to Yuval Noah Harari&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#questions-asked-to-yuval-noah-harari" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>What will be the trajectory of the USA under Trump?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If there&amp;rsquo;s any part of you that believes in any kind of a higher Divinity?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Would you have rather seen Kamala Harris become president?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you had to design the ideal American president, could you give us a list of points in terms of that person&amp;rsquo;s personality and that person&amp;rsquo;s mission?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Would you say that the onus lies with people like Sam Altman, Elon Musk, people who are central in the world of tech, to come up with ideas related to keeping the future of the human race safe?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What exactly does everyone need to know about AI?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Do you believe that India is kind of going back to that reality of becoming Vishwa Guru?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What is your opinion on PM Narendra Modi?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Do you think media content, these things, have a role to play in spreading the message of peace, the message of love?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What would be your message for those next people who will take the baton from you?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Will meditation on a global scale lead to human evolution?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How have the 1.years of also meditating added to your mind?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What have you written about in Sapiens?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What have you written about in 1.Lessons for the 1.t century?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What have you written about in Homo Deos?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Why is there a pigeon on the cover page of Nexus?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What would you say is the role of fiction and religion in focusing the mind?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What has been the result of this grind that you&amp;rsquo;ve put yourself through with meditation?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="thematic-summary-of-reponse-by-yuval-noah-harari">Thematic summary of reponse by Yuval Noah Harari&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#thematic-summary-of-reponse-by-yuval-noah-harari" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="on-political-leadership-and-global-dynamics">On Political Leadership and Global Dynamics:&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#on-political-leadership-and-global-dynamics" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>USA Under Trump:&lt;/strong> Harari describes Trump as a leader focused on power without regard for truth, which could make the USA more isolated and truth-averse. He warns of the potential for the U.S. to use its power unwisely under Trump’s leadership.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ideal American President:&lt;/strong> Harari refrains from prescribing characteristics for an ideal president, citing his lack of political expertise, but emphasizes that a president should have a global perspective, considering both U.S. interests and those of humanity, especially regarding AI and the climate crisis.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Opinion on PM Narendra Modi:&lt;/strong> Harari is cautious about making judgments without deep knowledge but expresses disappointment over India’s non-committal stance on the Russian invasion of Ukraine, expecting a leader from a historically anti-imperialist country to take a strong stand.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="on-technology-and-ai">On Technology and AI:&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#on-technology-and-ai" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dangers and Management of AI:&lt;/strong> Harari discusses the unprecedented power of AI, distinguishing it from other technologies due to its capacity to make decisions and innovate independently. He expresses concern over AI evolving beyond human control and influencing global power dynamics.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Responsibility in AI Development:&lt;/strong> He critiques the race to develop AI without adequate safety measures, citing the lack of trust among global competitors as a major risk, and calls for a global understanding and regulatory framework.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="on-spirituality-and-human-development">On Spirituality and Human Development:&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#on-spirituality-and-human-development" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Meditation and Human Evolution:&lt;/strong> Harari advocates for meditation as a tool for achieving personal clarity and truth but doubts its scalability as a global solution due to its inherent challenges and the potential for ritualization without understanding.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Spiritual Depth:&lt;/strong> He values spiritual depth and insists that true spiritual connections should manifest in actions rather than just words. Harari criticizes the use of religious or spiritual claims to justify negative or aggressive behaviors.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="on-societal-and-cultural-observations">On Societal and Cultural Observations:&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#on-societal-and-cultural-observations" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Role of Media:&lt;/strong> Harari believes that media plays a crucial role in shaping societal attitudes towards peace and love, advocating for content that presents a balanced view of reality, inclusive of its complexities and challenges.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Genetic Engineering:&lt;/strong> He discusses the potential social divisions that could result from genetic enhancements being accessible only to the wealthy, leading to a split in human capabilities and societal stratification.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="miscellaneous-insights">Miscellaneous Insights:&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#miscellaneous-insights" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Importance of Truth in Historical Narratives:&lt;/strong> Harari emphasizes the importance of acknowledging change and impermanence in historical and cultural identities, warning against the dangers of clinging to static or fictionalized narratives.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Personal Impact of Meditation:&lt;/strong> He credits meditation with providing the mental clarity needed to write his books and understand complex historical and technological trends deeply.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="my-critiques-on-the-responses-of-yuval-noah-harari">My Critiques on the responses of Yuval Noah Harari&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#my-critiques-on-the-responses-of-yuval-noah-harari" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a public intellectual, Yuval Noah Harari often points out ideal scenarios (global collaboration, trust, deep inner work) while simultaneously acknowledging systemic barriers that make these ideals difficult to achieve at scale. The contradictions don’t necessarily undermine his perspective but do highlight the real complexity and unresolved tensions in seeking global solutions. Many of these critiques/contradictions stem from broader philosophical and real political tensions like&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interview: Satya Nadella with BG2 - Dec-2024</title><link>https://localhost:1313/booksummary/Interview-Satya-Nadella-with--BG2-Dec-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/booksummary/Interview-Satya-Nadella-with--BG2-Dec-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://localhost:1313/assets/images/booksummary/7542-Interview-Satya-Nadella-with--BG2-Dec-2024.jpg" alt="Interview: Satya Nadella with BG, 2 Dec 2024">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="interview-satya-nadella-with-bg2---dec-2024">Interview: Satya Nadella with BG2 - Dec-2024&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#interview-satya-nadella-with-bg2---dec-2024" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If you want to hear from top technology leader around any of these questions then this interview is for you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is Agentic AI? Interview with Praveen Akkiraju at CXOTalk</title><link>https://localhost:1313/booksummary/Interview-What-is-Agentic-AI-Interview-Praveen-Akkiraji-at-CXOTalk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/booksummary/Interview-What-is-Agentic-AI-Interview-Praveen-Akkiraji-at-CXOTalk/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://localhost:1313/assets/images/booksummary/7538-Interview-What-is-Agentic-AI-Interview-Praveen-Akkiraji-at-CXOTalk.jpg" alt="What is Agentic AI? Interview with Praveen Akkiraju at CXOTalk">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="praveen-akkiraju-w-michael-krigsman--cxotalk---853">Praveen Akkiraju w/ Michael Krigsman @ CXOTalk - 853&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#praveen-akkiraju-w-michael-krigsman--cxotalk---853" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If you are interested in learning more about agentic AI, or you have any of these questions then without answer of fuzzy answer then this interview is for you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interview with Sundar Pichai @ Google at Dealbook Event 2024</title><link>https://localhost:1313/booksummary/interview-sundar-pichai-google-dealbook-event-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/booksummary/interview-sundar-pichai-google-dealbook-event-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://localhost:1313/assets/images/booksummary/7532-Interview-Sundar-Pichai-Google-Dealbook-Event-2024.jpg" alt="Interview-Sundar-Pichai-Google-Dealbook-Event-2024">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="key-themes-and-ideas-from-interview-with-sundar-pichai--google-at-dealbook-event-2024">Key Themes and Ideas from Interview with Sundar Pichai @ Google at Dealbook Event 2024&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#key-themes-and-ideas-from-interview-with-sundar-pichai--google-at-dealbook-event-2024" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>These themes illustrate Google’s strategies, challenges, and aspirations under Sundar Pichai&amp;rsquo;s leadership, with a strong focus on advancing AI responsibly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interview with Jensen Huang @ NVIDIA at Dealbook Event 2023</title><link>https://localhost:1313/booksummary/interview-jensen-huang-nvidia-dealbook-event-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nuno@n9o.xyz (Blowfish)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/booksummary/interview-jensen-huang-nvidia-dealbook-event-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://localhost:1313/assets/images/booksummary/7530-Interview-Jensen-Huang-NVIDIA-Dealbook-Event-2023.jpg" alt="Interview-Jensen-Huang-NVIDIA-Dealbook-Event-2024">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="insights-from-the-interview-with-jensen-huang--nvidia-at-dealbook-event-2023">Insights from the Interview with Jensen Huang @ NVIDIA at Dealbook Event 2023&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#insights-from-the-interview-with-jensen-huang--nvidia-at-dealbook-event-2023" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="theme-1-the-evolution-of-ai-computing">&lt;strong>Theme 1: The Evolution of AI Computing&lt;/strong>&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#theme-1-the-evolution-of-ai-computing" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Reinvention of Computing&lt;/strong>: Jensen emphasized that AI development isn&amp;rsquo;t just about designing new chips but about a comprehensive reinvention of computing systems, including software, hardware, and networking.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Transition to Generative Computing&lt;/strong>: Most current computing focuses on data retrieval, but the future involves combining retrieval with generative capabilities, transforming how systems operate globally.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Origins of AI Hardware&lt;/strong>: Nvidia&amp;rsquo;s first AI supercomputer, DGX, was designed for internal use but gained prominence when figures like Elon Musk requested it. It highlighted the potential of neural networks and deep learning.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="theme-2-ai-progress-and-challenges">&lt;strong>Theme 2: AI Progress and Challenges&lt;/strong>&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#theme-2-ai-progress-and-challenges" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Milestones in AI&lt;/strong>: Nvidia foresaw AI&amp;rsquo;s impact in 2012 with AlexNet, a neural network capable of unparalleled visual recognition. This breakthrough informed their investments in AI infrastructure.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Current AI Limitations&lt;/strong>: AI today excels in tasks like perception and pattern recognition but struggles with multi-step reasoning and decision trees. Addressing these gaps is a major focus for researchers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Predictions for AGI&lt;/strong>: Within five years, AI systems might perform tasks that meet basic human intelligence standards, pushing closer to Artificial General Intelligence (AGI).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="theme-3-corporate-governance-and-ai-ethics">&lt;strong>Theme 3: Corporate Governance and AI Ethics&lt;/strong>&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#theme-3-corporate-governance-and-ai-ethics" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lessons from OpenAI Drama&lt;/strong>: Huang underscored the importance of strong corporate governance, contrasting Nvidia’s for-profit structure with OpenAI’s non-profit roots, which faced challenges balancing innovation and control.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Regulation and Safety&lt;/strong>: AI must be managed with principles similar to those governing autonomous systems like airplanes, emphasizing redundancy, stress testing, and monitoring for safety.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="theme-4-geopolitical-and-strategic-challenges">&lt;strong>Theme 4: Geopolitical and Strategic Challenges&lt;/strong>&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#theme-4-geopolitical-and-strategic-challenges" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Chip Independence&lt;/strong>: Achieving supply chain independence for semiconductors could take decades. Nvidia uses 35,000 components sourced globally, underscoring the complexity of achieving autonomy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Export Regulations and China&lt;/strong>: Nvidia must comply with U.S. regulations limiting advanced chip exports to China. While these policies aim to safeguard national security, they risk spurring innovation in competing markets like China.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Surprise from Huawei&lt;/strong>: China’s progress with a 7nm chip was acknowledged, but Huang stated it reflected iterative advancements rather than a revolutionary leap.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="theme-5-nvidias-strategic-edge">&lt;strong>Theme 5: Nvidia’s Strategic Edge&lt;/strong>&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#theme-5-nvidias-strategic-edge" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Broad Vision&lt;/strong>: Nvidia sees AI as an ecosystem that integrates chips, software, and infrastructure. The company’s comprehensive approach positions it uniquely in the tech landscape.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Direct Reports Philosophy&lt;/strong>: Huang manages 50 direct reports to maintain fluid communication and reduce organizational hierarchy, ensuring swift decision-making and alignment.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Cultural Resilience&lt;/strong>: Huang’s philosophy emphasizes operating with a blend of ambition and caution, drawn from Nvidia’s history of overcoming adversity.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="theme-6-the-future-of-nvidia-and-ai">&lt;strong>Theme 6: The Future of Nvidia and AI&lt;/strong>&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#theme-6-the-future-of-nvidia-and-ai" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Reinvention of Data Centers&lt;/strong>: With AI reshaping computing, existing data centers worth trillions will require retooling, heralding a new era in infrastructure.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ignorance and Innovation&lt;/strong>: Huang highlighted how the initial ignorance of challenges allowed Nvidia to innovate fearlessly. This &amp;ldquo;teenage attitude&amp;rdquo; continues to drive their culture.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Long-Term Vision&lt;/strong>: Nvidia is doubling down on creating specialized AI systems for fields like drug discovery and chip design, ensuring the company remains at the forefront of AI-driven innovation.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="key-takeaways">&lt;strong>Key Takeaways&lt;/strong>&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#key-takeaways" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Nvidia&amp;rsquo;s leadership in AI stems from a holistic vision that goes beyond hardware to include software and systems integration.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Jensen Huang sees AI&amp;rsquo;s evolution as a fundamental shift comparable to the industrial revolution of computing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Balancing innovation with ethics, governance, and geopolitics will shape Nvidia’s future and the AI industry at large.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pkj-BLHs6dE">Full Youtube Video - Jensen Huang of Nvidia on the Future of A.I. in DealBook Summit 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>